Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we're going to be looking at another kind of science fiction lesson related to
今天我们要看另一节科幻课，内容与
aliens.
外星人有关。
That's right.
没错。
And I think in this lesson we'll actually have an alien sighting here at EnglishPod.
我觉得这节课里，我们EnglishPod还真会有外星人目击事件。
Right, an alien encounter.
对，一次外星人遭遇。
So we're going to be learning about the stars, we're going to be learning about aliens and
所以今天我们要学习关于星星的知识，还要学习关于外星人和
UFOs today.
UFO的知识。
That's right, and we're also going to learn some language that you can use to describe
没错，我们还会学习一些可以用来描述
negative results, things that happen that are bad.
负面结果、坏事发生的语言。
That's right.
对。
So let's start by looking at vocabulary preview.
那我们先从词汇预览开始吧。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, we have two words for you that we're going to hear in the dialogue.
好的，我们有两个词要在对话中听到。
And the first one is constellation.
第一个是星座。
Constellation.
星座。
A constellation.
一个星座。
A constellation is a group of stars that makes a shape and has a name.
星座是一组星星，它们组成一个形状并有一个名字。
The next one is earthlings.
下一个是地球人。
Earthlings.
地球人。
So earthlings are people who live on planet Earth.
所以地球人就是生活在地球上的人。
On Earth, exactly.
在地球上，没错。
And in the dialogue we're going to hear greetings earthlings.
在对话中我们会听到“问候地球人”。
This is the most typical phrase that you will hear in almost every single alien movie.
这是几乎每部外星人电影里最典型的台词。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's like saying hello people from Earth.
所以就像在说“你们好，来自地球的人们”。
Yes, every single alien in the world says this phrase.
是的，世界上每个外星人都说这句话。
So those are the two words that we are going to find in this dialogue today.
这就是我们今天对话中会出现的两个词。
So why don't we start and listen to what happens with our UFO experience.
那我们开始听听我们的UFO经历吧。
Oh honey, this is so romantic.
哦，亲爱的，这太浪漫了。
I have never seen like so many stars before.
我从没见过这么多星星。
It's beautiful.
真美。
See that constellation there?
看到那个星座了吗？
That's Orion.
那是猎户座。
And the very bright star?
那颗很亮的星星呢？
Well, it's not a star because it doesn't blink.
嗯，那不是星星，因为它不闪烁。
It's actually Venus.
它其实是金星。
What's that big flashy one?
那个很闪亮的是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think it's a UFO.
我觉得是UFO。
Greetings earthlings.
地球人，你们好。
I come from afar.
我从远方来。
From a distant galaxy known only to a few.
来自一个只有少数人知道的遥远星系。
Why are you here?
你为什么在这里？
Where did you come from?
你从哪里来？
We have been observing you for the last 3000 years.
我们已经观察你们三千年了。
We have seen the amazing capacity that humans have to create such wonders as the Taj Mahal
我们看到了人类创造奇迹的惊人能力，比如泰姬陵。
or masterpieces such as the Hafner Symphony.
或者像哈夫纳交响曲这样的杰作。
Unfortunately, your intelligence and creativity does not come without consequence.
不幸的是，你们的智慧和创造力并非没有代价。
Your ambition and desire for more will be your downfall and we are here to save your
你们的野心和对更多的渴望将是你们的毁灭，我们来这里是为了拯救你们的
planet from you.
星球，从你们手中。
You think you have us figured out?
你以为你了解我们？
What gives you the right to come and judge us?
你有什么权利来评判我们？
Who are you?
你是谁？
What are you?
你是什么？
and
以及
the Earth.
地球。
some of the negative results that are happening because of the human's behavior on earth,
一些因为人类在地球上的行为而产生的负面结果，
right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
And so one of the things they said was that your intelligence and creativity does not
所以他们说的其中一点是，你们的智慧和创造力并不
come without consequence.
来去无后果。
Consequence.
后果。
Without consequence.
无后果。
All right.
好的。
So the consequence of an action are basically the results.
所以，一个行为的后果基本上就是结果。
Yes, exactly.
是的，没错。
And here the phrase without consequence suggests the negative results.
而这里的“无后果”这个短语暗示了负面结果。
All right.
好的。
So the negative results from your actions.
所以，就是你行为带来的负面结果。
Very good.
很好。
What about our next word?
那我们的下一个词呢？
Well, the aliens also talked about human ambition.
嗯，外星人也谈到了人类的野心。
Ambition.
野心。
So, what is ambition exactly?
那么，野心到底是什么？
So ambition is the desire or the want for things to be better, to improve, to get rich,
所以，野心就是渴望或想要事情变得更好、改善、变富、
to be technologically advanced.
变得技术先进。
Okay.
好的。
So to want more.
所以就是想要更多。
Yeah.
是的。
You have ambitions in your life, in your professional life, in your personal life.
你在生活中、职业生涯中、个人生活中都有野心。
So basically we have ambition and we have desires and these are the reasons for our
所以基本上，我们有野心和欲望，而这些正是我们
downfall.
垮台的原因。
Okay.
好的。
So downfall.
所以，垮台。
Downfall.
垮台。
Will be your downfall.
将是你的垮台。
So the downfall of something is?
那么，某事的垮台是？
Something that causes failure.
导致失败的东西。
Okay.
好的。
So the loss of wealth or the loss of reputation or that it gets ruined.
所以，就是财富的损失、声誉的损失，或者被毁掉。
Exactly.
没错。
The downfall.
垮台。
We can say like for example, the downfall of the Roman empire.
我们可以说，比如，罗马帝国的垮台。
You know what, this guy is a great employee, but his lack of ambition was his downfall.
你知道吗，这家伙是个好员工，但他的缺乏野心是他的垮台。
Very good.
很好。
All right.
好的。
Coming up to our next word.
接下来是我们的下一个词。
The alien described that humans have a belligerent attitude.
外星人描述说，人类有一种好斗的态度。
Belligerent.
好斗的。
All right.
好的。
This is a very nice word.
这是一个非常好的词。
So why don't we listen to some examples of how we can use it in context?
那我们不如听一些例子，看看如何在语境中使用它？
Example one.
例子一。
Don't take that belligerent tone with me.
别用那种好斗的语气跟我说话。
I don't want to argue with you.
我不想跟你吵架。
Example two.
例子二。
Thomas is always so belligerent.
托马斯总是那么好斗。
It is impossible to talk to him.
跟他根本没法说话。
Example three.
例子三。
Stacey was fired for her belligerent attitude.
斯泰西因为她的好斗态度被开除了。
Okay.
好的。
So I can understand that it means sort of aggressive, having a strong willingness to
所以我能理解它有点攻击性的意思，有强烈的意愿去
fight.
打架。
Exactly.
没错。
A belligerent person, a belligerent attitude, a belligerent country.
一个好斗的人，一个好斗的态度，一个好斗的国家。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And our last word for today.
今天我们最后一个词。
Anguish.
痛苦。
So to cause great anguish.
所以是引起极大的痛苦。
To cause a lot of terrible emotional or physical pain.
引起很多可怕的情感或身体上的痛苦。
Okay.
好的。
So it is a synonym of pain, of suffering.
所以它是疼痛、苦难的同义词。
Yeah.
是的。
But really intense suffering.
但指的是非常强烈的痛苦。
Really intense.
非常强烈。
Why don't we give a few examples?
我们举几个例子吧？
The end of his marriage caused him great anguish.
他婚姻的结束给他带来了极大的痛苦。
Or for example, the loss of his dog caused him great anguish.
或者比如，他失去了狗，给他带来了极大的痛苦。
Okay.
好的。
So anguish.
所以是痛苦。
Alright.
好了。
So we've covered five great words on Language Takeaway today.
今天我们“语言小贴士”部分涵盖了五个很棒的词。
Why don't we move on now to putting it together?
我们不如现在进入“融会贯通”环节？
Putting it together.
融会贯通。
Okay.
好的。
We're going to look at three phrases that we heard in the dialogue and see how we can
我们要看看对话中听到的三个短语，并了解如何
use them in different contexts.
在不同情境中使用它们。
So the aliens were praising some of the masterpieces that the humans have created, right?
所以外星人在赞美人类创造的一些杰作，对吧？
Right.
对。
He said, you humans create such wonders as the Taj Mahal, blah, blah, blah.
他说，你们人类创造了像泰姬陵之类的奇迹，等等等等。
Okay.
好的。
So let's look at this phrase, such wonders as.
那我们来看看这个短语：such wonders as。
Alright.
好的。
So we have a noun here, a wonder.
这里有一个名词，wonder。
An amazing thing.
一件令人惊叹的事物。
An amazing structure.
一个令人惊叹的建筑。
Yes.
是的。
He says such wonders as.
他说的是 such wonders as。
Now we can change this noun and replace it with another one, right?
现在我们可以换掉这个名词，用另一个词代替，对吧？
Yeah.
嗯。
We can replace that noun with anything.
我们可以用任何东西替换那个名词。
So why don't we hear a few examples?
那我们听几个例子吧？
Example one.
例子一。
To finish this house, we need such materials as cement, wood, and steel.
要完成这栋房子，我们需要像水泥、木材和钢材这样的材料。
Example two.
例子二。
I need to write a report on a social topic such as psychology, health, or marriage.
我需要写一篇关于社会话题的报告，比如心理学、健康或婚姻。
Example three.
例子三。
Companies have found that social networking sites such as Facebook and Twitter are great
公司发现，像Facebook和Twitter这样的社交网站是很好的
marketing opportunities.
营销机会。
So this is a really useful structure to use when you want to give examples of many different
所以当你想要列举许多不同事物的例子时，这是一个非常有用的结构。
things.
Okay.
好的。
So when a civilian was criticizing the humans, the guy said, what gives you the right to
所以当一个平民在批评人类时，那个人说，你有什么权利来评判我们？
come and judge us?
So interesting phrase.
一个有趣的短语。
What gives you the right?
你有什么权利？
All right.
好的。
So if I tell you what gives you the right to, and then a verb.
所以如果我对你说 what gives you the right to，然后加一个动词。
Yeah.
嗯。
What am I saying there?
我这是在说什么？
You're basically saying you don't have the right to do this.
你基本上是在说你没有权利做这件事。
You shouldn't do this.
你不应该做这件事。
Why are you doing it?
你为什么这么做？
Or why do you want to have this control over me?
或者你为什么想这样控制我？
Yep.
是的。
So when would you use this phrase?
那你什么时候会用这个短语？
If somebody is trying to control you or maybe somebody is judging you or doing something
如果有人试图控制你，或者有人在评判你，或者做一些
to you against your will, maybe, you would say, what gives you the right to take my phone
违背你意愿的事情，你可能会说，你有什么权利拿走我的手机
away?
？
What gives you the right to tell me what to do?
你有什么权利告诉我该做什么？
All right.
好的。
It's a good phrase to tell that other person that they shouldn't do that.
这是一个很好的短语，用来告诉对方他们不应该那样做。
They're doing something unfair.
他们在做不公平的事。
Unfair.
不公平。
Okay.
好的。
And our next phrase is very similar.
我们的下一个短语非常相似。
Who are you to play God with our fate?
你以为你是谁，凭什么对我们的命运指手画脚？
Okay.
好的。
So I want to look at this.
所以我想看看这个。
To play God.
扮演上帝。
All right.
好的。
So to play God is making these arbitrary decisions.
所以“扮演上帝”就是做出这些武断的决定。
Like he is the master of everything.
就好像他是一切的主宰。
Right.
对。
Controlling everything.
控制一切。
But this phrase, who are you to?
但这个短语，“你以为你是谁？”
So basically saying you don't have the power or authority to do this.
基本上就是说你没有权力或权威做这件事。
And you can use it in exactly the same way.
你可以用完全相同的方式使用它。
Who are you to tell me what to do?
你以为你是谁，凭什么告诉我该做什么？
Who are you to take away my phone?
你以为你是谁，凭什么拿走我的手机？
Exactly.
没错。
So you don't have the power to do this.
所以你没有权力这么做。
Very good.
非常好。
So these phrases are a little bit aggressive, almost belligerent, wouldn't you say?
所以这些短语有点咄咄逼人，几乎好斗，你不觉得吗？
A little bit.
有一点。
But I guess if you are being treated unfair or if you are angry at a situation, it would
但我想如果你受到不公平对待，或者你对某个情况感到愤怒，用这个短语
be a good phrase to use to put your point across.
来表达你的观点会很好。
Yes.
是的。
And as we saw, these humans are pretty angry.
正如我们所见，这些人非常生气。
So why don't we listen again as they're telling the aliens, who are you to do this to us?
那我们再听一遍，他们对外星人说，你以为你是谁，凭什么这样对我们？
Oh, honey, this is so romantic.
哦，亲爱的，这太浪漫了。
I have never seen like so many stars before.
我从未见过这么多星星。
It's beautiful.
真美。
See that constellation there?
看到那个星座了吗？
That's Orion.
那是猎户座。
And the very bright star?
那颗很亮的星星呢？
Well, it's not a star because it doesn't blink.
嗯，那不是星星，因为它不闪烁。
That's actually Venus.
那实际上是金星。
What's that big, flashy one?
那个又大又闪的是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I think it's a UFO.
我觉得是UFO。
Greetings, Earthlings.
你们好，地球人。
I come from afar, from a distant galaxy known only to a few.
我从远方来，来自一个只有少数人知道的遥远星系。
Why are you here?
你们为什么在这里？
Where did you come from?
你们从哪里来？
We have been observing you for the last three thousand years.
我们已经观察你们三千年了。
We have seen your amazing capacity that humans have to create such wonders as the Taj Mahal
我们看到了人类创造奇迹的惊人能力，比如泰姬陵
or masterpieces such as the Hafner Symphony.
或像哈夫纳交响曲这样的杰作。
Unfortunately, your intelligence and creativity does not come without consequence.
不幸的是，你们的智慧和创造力并非没有后果。
Your ambition and desire for more will be your downfall, and we are here to save your
你们的野心和对更多的渴望将是你们的毁灭，我们来这里是为了拯救你们的
planet from you.
星球免受你们的破坏。
You think you have us figured out?
你以为你了解我们？
What gives you the right to come and judge us?
你有什么权利来评判我们？
Who are you to play God with our fate?
你以为你是谁，凭什么对我们的命运指手画脚？
Silence, human.
闭嘴，人类。
It is that belligerent attitude that has caused years of pain and anguish among yourselves.
正是这种好斗的态度导致了你们之间多年的痛苦和折磨。
Now you will pay the price.
现在你们要付出代价。
Okay so UFOs and constellations and stars and planets.
好的，所以UFO、星座、星星和行星。
Have you ever had an encounter with one of these?
你曾经遇到过这些吗？
Well definitely not an encounter with a UFO but maybe with some of the wonders of the
嗯，肯定没遇到过UFO，但可能遇到过一些夜空的
night sky.
奇观。
What happened?
发生了什么？
Well you know when I was small I used to have my vacations up in northern Canada and because
嗯，你知道我小时候经常去加拿大北部度假，因为
it was so far away from the city it was really dark and you could see all of these shooting
那里离城市很远，非常暗，你可以看到所有这些流星
stars so these stars moving across the sky and lighting up the whole sky with their brightness
这些星星划过天空，用它们的光芒照亮整个天空，
and it really is one of the most beautiful things I've ever seen.
这真的是我见过的最美的东西之一。
So shooting stars those are like balls of fire that move across the sky right?
所以流星就像火球划过天空，对吧？
Yeah exactly and I saw once actually I was in an astronomy class and turned around and
是的，没错，我实际上有一次在天文学课上，转过身
over the horizon like at the end of the sky where the sky meets the earth I saw this huge
看到地平线上——天空与大地相接的地方——有一个巨大的
ball of fire move across the sky and it looked like it landed in the field next to us it
火球划过天空，看起来它落在了我们旁边的田野里，
was so close.
离得那么近。
Wow that's nice.
哇，真不错。
Yeah pretty amazing.
是的，相当惊人。
Well I imagine that it is really amazing and I guess Canada is the place to be when you
嗯，我想那确实很惊人，而且我觉得加拿大是看这些东西
want to see these things.
的好地方。
I know we've got like northern lights, we've got shooting stars, lots of stuff.
我知道我们有北极光、流星，很多东西。
Alright so what about you guys?
好的，那你们呢？
You should tell us if you've ever seen a shooting star or a meteor or something of this type
你们应该告诉我们，你们是否见过流星或陨石之类的
of astronomy things right?
天文现象，对吧？
Or even a UFO.
甚至UFO也行。
Alright so come to our website englishpod.com be sure to leave your questions and your comments
好的，所以来我们的网站 englishpod.com，一定要留下你们的问题和评论，
and Erica and I are there to answer any questions or doubts.
我和Erica会在那里回答任何问题或疑惑。
So thanks for downloading you guys and until next time goodbye!
谢谢你们的下载，下次再见！